i would like to let you know that if you
haven't updated your browser you
probably should do it right now as
quickly as possible like yesterday a
couple of days ago google released a
security fix for a zero day
vulnerability that was affecting google
chrome but it turns out that other
browsers are affected as well and from
the clues that google gives us it looks
like this vulnerability might be a big
one zero day vulnerability means that
this is a never seen before security
hall it means that no one or almost
nobody knows about this and also means
that people have had zero days to update
their systems qualis which is a platform
that tracks vulnerabilities says that
the successful exploitation of this
security hall might result in the
complete compromise of the system this
means a complete takeover of the
computer which is something that might
already be happening because google has
said that they are aware that there is
an exploit already for this security
hall in the wild this means it's out
there in the internet and some people
might be getting affected already by
this problem is not only affecting
google chrome is actually affecting
other browsers as well because the
problem the security hole is not in
chrome itself is actually in the
chromium v8 and javascript engine many
of the browsers that we use like google
chrome microsoft edge brave browser
naver whale samsung internet vivaldi
share the same core they were all made
using something called chromium which is
an open source browser
all these browsers took chromium and
added some extra features on top of it
now those browsers might look different
and have some different features like
for example google chrome if you use it
you can link it very well with your
google account but if you use for
example brave browser you get adblock
already installed by default and more
privacy so all these browsers maybe look
different but they share the same core
and this means that if that core that
all the browsers use has a problem this
means that all these browsers have a
problem as well and this is exactly what
the problem is the problem is on
chromium which is the core that
everybody shares and more specifically
in the v8 javascript engine that
chromium uses to execute javascript v8
is an open source javascript engine that
is written in c and that is used by
chromium but also node.js our cpus of
course do not understand javascript so
when you go to a website that uses
javascript or when you use node.js v8 is
the one that is going to read your
javascript code it is going to compile
it to bytecode and using something
called turbofan is going to compile that
to machine code and it's somewhere there
in v8 where this vulnerability is which
might mean that to trigger the
vulnerability all the hackers would have
to do is just run some malicious
javascript code browsers like firefox
and safari don't use v8 they use their
own javascript engines the javascript
engine of a firefox is called spider
monkey and the javascript engine of
safari is called javascript core so this
means that if you're using firefox or
safari you are completely safe and there
is nothing to worry about today now i
would like to show you how this
vulnerability is exploited what is the
code that makes this security hall
happen and what is the worst thing that
an attacker could do to our computer the
problem is that i can't google is
keeping all the details about this zero
day secret google is basically buying
time so that more than three billion
google chrome users have enough time to
update their systems since as we saw
before there is an exploit out there in
the wild they are aware of this so they
know that this is already being used to
compromise some systems three billion
that's a lot of users and this doesn't
count all the other browsers that are
using chromium this only counts google
chrome itself that's insane the only
thing that we know is that this security
vulnerability is caused by something
called type confusion type confusion
happens when the program allocates a
variable or creates a variable with a
specific type but later accesses that
variable with an incompatible type now
this makes the system crash and
potentially might allow the hacker to
execute some arbitrary code but even
though we don't know the actual details
about this zero day we can tell it's a
big one because google doesn't usually
push us an update that contains only one
security fix usually chrome updates
contain many small fixes this update has
only one fix and it was pushed really
quickly after receiving the report of
this vulnerability by an anonymous
researcher we can also tell that this
one is a big deal when the u.s cyber
security agency orders all federal
agencies to update their browsers
immediately this is not the first zero
day that chrome has had this year back
in february the chrome team pushed a fix
for a zero day vulnerability that was
being used by north korean hackers for
six weeks before being discovered so to
conclude if you use any chromium based
browser like for example google chrome
or microsoft edge brave browser never
will samsung internet the value or opera
make sure you update your systems right
now most of these browsers have already
pushed the updates and usually these
browsers have auto updates enabled so
you don't have to do anything to
download the update but you might have
to restart your browser for the update
to take effect
most chromium browsers can be updated by
going to settings and about
there you can see if there are any
updates pending and you can also check
the chromium version that your browser
is running the vulnerable chrome version
is this one right here so check if you
are running something higher than this
and if you're not click the update
button i wish i had more details about
the exploit and what is the actual code
that triggers this vulnerability but for
now everything is secret and it makes
sense why let me know in the comments if
you would like me to do a follow-up
video on this when we know more details
later and that's it for this video if
you like the way i explain things and
you would like to code for free with me
then please click the link below because
there you're going to find free courses
on things like javascript react react
native python redox graphql go among
many other things thank you as always
for watching stay happy stay free stay
healthy eat kimchi come change that
salah see you on the next one bye